Andrii Khorishko

Full Stack Web Developer

Summary of Qualifications

Dedicated and efficient full-stack developer with more than 10 years of experience in application layers, presentation layers and databases. Certified in both F/E and B/E technologies. Spearheaded the successful conversion from LAMP to MERN, reducing latency by 40% and increasing database administrator effectiveness by 20%. Would like to further improve his HTML5 and CSS3 skills as a future full-stack developer at Atmospheric Solutions.

Work Experience

Leader of IT Developer Team, Full Stack Developer

May 2019–June 2022

Berkeley, California, United States

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Led a team consisting of 5 members and published a React and Vue theme.
- Worked as a backend developer, performed final testing of the backend and frontend of the website and optimized the speed and performance of the website.
- Created Mockup design of the website with a designer

Full Stack Developer at Diffco – US IT company

May 2014-June 2019

Sunnyvale, California, United States

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Developed full-stack web applications that processed, analyzed and visualized data.
- Collaborated with backend and frontend developers, quality assurance testers and the CTO as needed.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades.
- Planned, wrote and debugged web applications and software with absolute accuracy.

Key Achievements

• Spearheaded transition from LAMP stack to MEAN stack, reducing latency by 40% and increasing database admin effectiveness by 20%.

Junior Full Stack Developer at Diffco - US IT company

December 2011–April 2014

Sunnyvale, California, United States

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Maximized efficiency, data quality, scope, usability and flexibility of applications.
- Utilized various ideas from distributed computing, large-scale design, real-time data processing, data storage, ML and AI to solve challenging data problems.
- Managed, optimized and updated PHP databases as needed.
- Developed app integration with REST / SOAP and other APIs for Google Maps, social media logins, payment processors and other services.

Education

University of California, Bachelor of Computer Science

Graduation: 2011

Relevant Coursework: Web Page Development, Relational Database Design & SQL, Data Engineering, Advanced Software Programming.

Uzhhorod National University

Zakarpattia, Ukraine Graduation: 2006 Studied Computer Science.

Key Skills

- Google Compute Engine
- Android and iOS App Development
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, React, Vue, Angular,
- Express.js, Python, Golang, .Net Framework
- Bootstrap, Tailwind, Mui
- My SQL, Mongo DB, Postgres SQL, Microsoft SQL Database
- AWS, Azure, Agile, Kubernetes,

Certifications

- Full-Stack Web Development with React Certification
- Front End Web Development Certificate
- Back End Web Development Certificate
- AWS Certified DevOps Engineer Professional
- Free Code Camp Full Stack Development Certification

Languages

English: FluentUkrainian: Native